I'm here with Mr. Phil right here, he's owner of Clean Floor Coatings. We've gotten 37
as showed appointments so far. Does that sound right?
That sounds exactly right.
Okay, and I know the closing rate has been pretty good. What has been the closing rate
on these appointments approximately?
Hard to tell because they're not immediate, but I'd say immediately
on the first call is running about 80% and I get some follow-up afterwards.
Okay, so we're not done closing them. And then what was the experience like
working with us with Appointly Solutions?
The first week for me was a little scary. I think I had two or three appointments.
There were small jobs and I projected and said, man, maybe this isn't going to work.
But we hung in there and I remember one morning I woke up and I had six appointments that you'd
made for me in the previous day. And I went on a couple and the math worked out. I said, okay,
if this works out, it's going to be good. And then I walked into another one that was four or
five times the average size of my job out in a community that's an hour away from me.
And it's the kind of job that would make my whole week. It's enough revenue for me to hit a week's
target. And I knew that you and I had found something here that works really well for both
of us.
That's awesome, man. Yeah, we're trying to do the consistent stuff. We're trying to hit
singles every day, but we'll get a home run every week as well.
Sure. And then I also factored into, okay, if I'm at an 80% close rate
and this is how much the job is and this is what it cost me, it makes sense. But what I
didn't anticipate is that the job you got me into in some neighborhoods turns into two or three
jobs. So the customer acquisition costs, if I really wanted to confuse somebody, I'd say my
close rate is probably 130% because every appointment that I've gone on has averaged more
than one job, just in the affiliate space of word of mouth and getting in the door.
So this got the ball rolling. To be honest, when I first started, I was doing maybe two
or three floors a week. And it's a dilemma for me, because I don't do these floors myself,
I have to hire a staff. So the question is, do you pay guys for five days, or do you
pay them for two or three and know that they're going to go out and find another job and it's
going to be really hard to get them back. So when I started working with you, I'm now
booked up for five days for the next three weeks in a row. So it changed my business model
instead of this being a thing where I was hoping to get business, I now can staff
accordingly, I can buy inventory in a better place. And I'm hoping to build up my Google reviews and
my presence online, the byproduct is way better than one to one. That's awesome, man. I love to
hear that. And typically a lot of what I'll hear with someone that maybe hasn't done paid advertising,
or at least for this business, or has had a bad experiences, they'll tell me, hey, look,
this is pretty expensive to acquire new customers, right? What I would ask you is, what has it
done for growing the business? Besides just being profitable and just making some money,
what has it done for growing the business, having a steady pipeline, having appointments
every day already set for you? Let me address the costs. For starters, it seems like a ton of
money seems unreasonable how much money it is. But here's what you're doing. You know, if you're
buying, you know, Google ads or Facebook ads, you're buying top of the funnel people, you're
buying, you know, raw materials that you're gonna have to do a lot of work and convert into
dollars. So what I'm doing with you guys is I'm buying people that are at the bottom of the funnel,
they're ready to close. I can weed out, I don't have to go on a lot of superfluous calls. I don't
have to do a lot of extra stuff. And I have accounts where I walk in on Thursday to do a quote.
And on Monday, they're running a credit card to pay for the job we did that Monday. So you
lead isn't a lead. Like if somebody says, how much does a lead cost? This isn't a lead. This
is somebody that's at the bottom of the funnel, ready to make a buying decision. And I know,
for me personally, I need to keep my staff running, let's say at a minimum of four days a week.
So I need six, seven jobs a week to keep them going four days, we do two a day, a lot of days.
And that allows me to I have fixed expenses, I have a warehouse, I have a payment to make
on my grinder in my truck. It allows me to spread that fixed expenses over more jobs.
It allows me to keep my staff busy. And it allows me to get out in communities where people are seeing
me more. And I know that if seasonally, we've been doing this during a really good time of the year,
if this slows down, that I'll get on a phone with you, which you're always willing to do with me
every day if I need it. And we'll just throttle this thing up, we'll just add another geography
another city to it or we'll increase the paid ads. Or a product or we'll go after another
type of homeowner. Right. So I feel like I'm not at the will of the internet to determine whether
I have a good week, I just have to, you know, do the math and say this is what we need to do this
week to get to the number that we want to get to 100%. And you touch on appointments versus leads.
And that's something that I might undersell sometimes to business owners is what work what
you're getting for an appointment. So talk a little bit about what you're getting for an
appointment. What's the time when you walk in when you have an appointment? What's the
conversation like? Sure. Well, in the past, you know, when I got leads, it would come in.
It might be somebody, for example, they filled out a Facebook form and was reluctant to give
me their phone number, like they literally wouldn't give me their phone number, or they would
text me a square footage and say, you know, I got 440 square feet, what's your lowest price? Can
you beat this other guy? And, you know, they're leads, but they're not going to be readily
converted into revenue. And what's happened with you and I is I get a verbose, you know,
two paragraphs from you that says I talked to this guy, he just moved into his house.
He's got a lot of stuff that he's going to need to move out. You know, they have some damage,
and they're going to need to have this spalling repaired. And when I show up these people, and I
was kidding with you before, you know, they think that you and I see each other in the office
every day, they say, Oh, yeah, Jacob told me you'd be like this. And they're ready to buy there.
They've built up a level of comfort with our company. We also have a tick in our company,
we have an office so that if you call somebody answers the safety net underneath people, we
don't have a lot of Google reviews, we haven't been in business a long time. So the comfort
that they get by talking to you and having a phone number to call and you'll call them back.
And, you know, we show up for the appointment, the objection that I expect to get, which is that,
you know, you're not as well established as these other companies never comes up for me.
It's been really comfortable. And so it's not a lead. It's not an appointment, I'm getting to go see
somebody that's ready to buy epoxy flooring. That's how it's worked out for me so far. And to your
credit, like you've ruled out a lot of people, you said, well, this lady wanted to do this,
but she's waiting for her check to come in in February. So I didn't book an appointment.
And I appreciate that. You've done it a couple of times with things like that, or jobs that are
too small, or people that lowball you on the phone, and say, you know, I'm going to do this,
but I'm not going to pay more than $2,000. So don't come out here if you're going to ask for
more. Like you screen those people like the day that you screen that you saved me two and a half
hours. And you know, 100 miles on my car, and allowed me to be out in front of somebody else that might
buy instead of wasting the day chasing somebody that's going to allow me to lose money doing
their job. Absolutely. Yeah, that's the goal. The goal is if it's you, the owner or a salesperson
on your team, either way, they should only in my mind, be only talking to people that are going to
get the job done. They're looking for the best price or they're looking for the best product,
but they will actually want the job done. And that's kind of the service that we provide is
keeping your calendar full with people that actually are looking to buy and anybody that
isn't, they still get followed up with, we still have a conversation with them. We still inform them
about the product. We still help them out, but it just might not be something that is
ready to go onto your calendar. And that's kind of what you're getting
there with us as well. And to touch on the experience for the customer. Yes, it does help
when they're seeing an advertisement of your company, then they're having a conversation,
then they're looking at your website, and then they're seeing you in person. And all of it
is the same messaging. You're talking about the same product. You're talking about the same
experience. You're letting them know, Hey, I'm from this area. They already knew you were from that
area. So we're giving them a congruent experience. And of course, that's, that's going to be
completely different than, you know, applying on one of these websites online or submitting a bid
online or calling a franchise and they, they just show up for an appointment and they don't
kind of give them the time of day, really. Or AI or an answering service where the people on
a phone don't know anything. So the word I would use for this is we're conveying integrity,
like that consistent message and the people you're talking to are all,
you're overly competent for what you're doing. And I'm overly confident for what I'm doing.
Like they're getting that message. If you literally were just one of my people in the office,
like you would not be able to answer the difference between polyurea and epoxy or,
you know, tell people what, what the questions that they're asking, what the answers would be.
So, the immediate impression they get with you is that we're a very competent company and we know
what we're doing. Perfect. Yeah. That's definitely what we're going for. And, with the quality
of the appointments that we're getting, you mentioned sometimes not putting somebody on your
calendar. A lot of folks that I speak with, you know, they're, they're skeptical because they
might think that, okay, you're saying you're qualifying these appointments, but what does this
really look like on my end? I know that we've had situations where if it wasn't a big enough square
footage, then I booked it the appointment in for free. If it wasn't something that was within
your radius, then we didn't put it on your calendar at all. Can you attest
to that level of quality? I actually want to cite an example. I had a
lady that I went to see that you booked the appointment and she seemed like a really good
customer. When I got there, she needed to have concrete work done on her driveway. She said, well,
I'm going to have you do this and then I'm going to add this other thing and you can come back and
do that too. And, I said, that's not how it works. You know, you got to get your driveway the
way you want it. We have to give the, concrete two months to cure, and then I'll come
back and we'll measure after you're done. And I talked to you about that. you know, I, I
didn't like going out there. I didn't like, you know, and, and the first thing you said to me
was, well, I won't charge you for that. That, you know, I understand that I don't want you to have
to pay for that appointment. That wasn't a quality appointment. And I knew then that like, this stuff
is going to continue to happen. I mean, if you do this enough, you're going to run into, you
know, opportunities that aren't opportunities, but I know that you and I, as, as business
people, we're going to work this out so that it's profitable for you. That's really important
to me. I want to, you know, make sure this is worth your time and attention and you're making
sure it's profitable for me. and you're not looking at me as a, you know, how much revenue you
can get. You're like, how can I really help that guy's business grow so that we can have a long,
sustained situation. and, and we've, you know, renegotiated this process as it went to say,
make sure this is good for both of us. 100%. Yeah. Final question. What would you say to
anybody that has kind of been burned in the past or maybe it's on the fence about
getting burned again? Well, it's a really low cost to entry to get in and give it a try. So I would
say buy yourself 30 days and give it a try. I work with other marketing agencies and I think this is
why they don't work. Okay. They come to me with a plan that's between $199 a month and $2,000 a
month. And their whole model is built on scalability. Like I'm going to talk to the owner. He's
going to get me in. We're going to get this thing going. And then as soon as it's going,
they're going to push me down to the level where somebody that's offshore or they're just going
to try to see how many of me they can get and churn. And, so my customer experience, like I get
brought in at one level of, expectation, like that the owner cares about my business.
And then a couple months later, of course, for him to make his nut, you know, he's got to have,
you know, 10 new me's every month. Your experience, I would say, as opposed to
scalability is on sustainability. Like, the whole month that we're doing this, it's not about
how much money you're going to make this month or how much money I'm going to make this month.
It's really, I've talked to you almost every day on how can we build this model so that it's
sustainable so that what we're doing now, we're going to do for 52 weeks a year that we could
take Phil from one truck to three trucks. We can go from having five appointments to having
15 appointments. And it's a different kind of scalability. It's not to go get a whole
bunch more customers at a lower rate. It's to maintain the rate. I want to pay the rate
that I'm paying. I just want to do it for more and more trucks and more and more jobs.
And I know that your interests and my interests are a hundred percent aligned here.
And I think the mistake with a lot of agencies is that they're not aligned. You want to create
a recurring revenue source that you can put the least amount of personal time into as possible.
and that seems to be the model for agencies. Like a lot of people start out with a really good
experience. And when you hear what happened, you understand like, Oh, that's the owner of
that business trying to figure out how to ramp this up. but it's not sustainable. It's not
sustainable for me and it's not sustainable for them. I've had agencies that put a lot of work
into building content for us. And then, you know, it stops working for me and I have to,
have to move on. I don't feel like that's the case with you and I. I feel like, you know,
we're doing more. I don't even look at the creative. I don't know what the creative is.
I don't need to, because I know the result is that I'm going to wake up tomorrow on an average
day. I mean, you could do the math. I don't, you know it better than I do, but I'd say
anywhere it's between two and six appointments will be booked for me between now and noon
tomorrow. and, so why would I even go look at the creative? Why would I care
what, you know, what you're doing on Facebook? Because I know the result is that I get to go
to people's house that are ready to buy epoxy jobs and have an expectation that I'm not going
to be the cheapest guy, that it's not going to be the fastest job. They expect to pay a fair
price and get a really good product. And I feel like you treat me with the same
customer service that I treat those people with. Like that's the deal. Like I've got to kiss
somebody else's butt down the stream. and it's really nice that I feel like you attend to
my account the same way I attend to theirs.